meatvideo.in 2019-03-21

# Privacy Policy - Mercy For Animals

Thank you for your interest in Mercy For Animals. Your privacy is important to us. Please read below for details regarding how we utilize the information you provide to us. For users accessing this website from the European Union, this Privacy Policy also provides instructions on how to request the removal of your data or a readout of your data as required under the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”).

Please also note that this policy applies only to websites and publications maintained by MFA and not to external sites or affiliated organizations and companies. Refer to the privacy policies of the respective organizations and companies for more information.

##### How does MFA collect my information?

MFA may collect your information directly through submission forms on our webpages or passively through digital tools including Cookies and Pixels. For users visiting our webpage from the European Union, MFA relies on your consent as a lawful basis for collecting your information. Please follow the instructions contained in this Privacy Policy to withdraw consent or to limit our ability to receive certain types of information through our digital tools or the tools of our third-party partners.

##### Opportunities to submit information

There are various places on our websites and other publications (both online and print) where you are able to enter personal information in order to receive information relevant to your interests and be updated about important activity at MFA, including the following:

  * E-newsletter sign-up forms
  * _Vegetarian Starter Guide_ request forms
  * Online store
  * Donation pages
  * Contests, surveys, and petitions
  * Vegetarian pledge forms
  * Volunteer sign-up forms

By submitting your contact information through these various forms, you consent to receiving emails from MFA relating to your interests and to receiving other content from MFA relating to important developments in the animal rights movement or to volunteer opportunities, demonstrations, or similar activities.

##### Cookies

In addition to information that you submit, like most websites, MFA uses “cookies” to remember some details about visitors, such as their language preferences or the contents of their shopping carts in the online store. Cookies are used for the limited purpose of facilitating your use of this website and to allow you to access our content with ease. These are not used to store personal information and are not tied to any personally identifiable information, such as your name or your IP address. These cookies may, however, allow us to obtain basic information, such as your general geographic location, the way that you reached our website, and your activity on our website. MFA’s website may not honor “do not track” signals that it receives from visitors’ web browsers unless honoring such requests is mandated by local law. MFA also relies on information obtained from cookies to perform ongoing analysis and improve our website and to tailor our content to your interests.

##### Pixels

MFA works with third-party partners such as Facebook, Salesforce, Shopify and Google to tailor our content to your preferences when you visit our websites through links in advertisements on our third-party partners’ websites. This information, which may include language and location information, allows us to work to customize our content and also helps guide our decisions regarding the effectiveness of certain content so that we can display content that you are interested in receiving. MFA also relies on information obtained from pixels to perform ongoing analysis and improve our website and tailor our content to your interests.

##### How is this information used?

Information supplied in contact forms is used to send you updates and information about MFA and our campaigns and programs, including events, activities, appeals, donation opportunities, vegetarian eating tips, and news. For your convenience and security, information supplied via donation forms is also shared with MFA’s third-party partner Engaging Networks, a leading provider of online fundraising and advocacy tools for nonprofits.

We also use information to improve our websites and campaigns. By collecting visitor behavior statistics, we are able to measure interest in our various campaigns and programs and use this information to better serve you and make our advocacy efforts more effective.

##### How can I stop providing this information?

You can opt out of using cookies and third-party pixels set by participating members at <http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/>. All of MFA’s third-party partners that we rely on for information obtained through pixels are members, and opting out through this centralized website will allow you to disable tracking through their tools. Opting out of interest-based advertising does not mean you will no longer see advertising online. It does mean that the company or companies from which you opt out will no longer show ads that have been tailored to your interests.

If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows you to automatically decline cookies or be given the choice of declining or accepting the transfer to your computer of a particular cookie (or cookies) from a particular site. You can choose whether to accept cookies by changing the settings on your browser or, depending on your jurisdiction, by managing your tracking preferences as noted in a separately posted cookie statement or via a posted cookie manager. If, however, you do not accept cookies, you may experience some inconvenience in your use of the online services. For example, we may not be able to recognize your computer, and you may need to log in every time you visit. You also may not receive advertising or other offers from us that are relevant to your interests and needs. At this time, we do not respond to browser “Do-Not-Track” signals except in jurisdictions where we are required to do so by law.

##### How can I request, correct, or delete my personal information?

MFA will respond to all requests to provide records of available information, correct erroneous information, or delete personal information, which can be submitted by sending an email with the request to our optimization team at [dataprivacy@mercyforanimals.org](mailto:dataprivacy@mercyforanimals.org). We will respond to all requests within the legally mandated timeframe.

##### How is my information protected?

MFA uses advanced security protocols to ensure the privacy of your information. We do not rent, trade, or sell email addresses. Any financial information is sent via a secure server and encrypted for your protection. MFA does not see, store, or retain credit card numbers. Credit card information is submitted directly to WePay.com, a third party that processes the financial transactions. For more information about the information security offered by WePay.com, you may visit their website at <https://go.wepay.com/> and view their Terms of Service.

We work with other reputable organizations and occasionally make names and mailing addresses of donors available to them. If you prefer that your information not be exchanged, please email us at [dataprivacy@mercyforanimals.org](mailto:dataprivacy@mercyforanimals.org), unsubscribe from MFA’s mailing list by clicking the unsubscribe link in any email from MFA, or call [866-632-6446](tel:1-866-632-6446).

##### Your rights with respect to your personal information

You may have certain rights regarding your personal information, subject to local law. These include the rights to access your personal information; correct the information we hold about you; erase your personal information; restrict our use of your personal information; object to our use of your personal information; withdraw your consent for us to use your personal information, if applicable; receive your personal information in a usable electronic format and transmit it to a third party (right to data portability); and lodge a complaint with your local data protection authority (if applicable).

##### Unsubscribing from our mailing list

If you are currently receiving regular emails from us and wish to unsubscribe, you may do so by clicking the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of the emails.

##### Notice for minors

Minors should not submit their personal information, such as their names, addresses, phone numbers, or other personal identifying information, through this website. In the event you have inadvertently submitted such information you can delete any content you have posted by contacting Mercy For Animals at [dataprivacy@mercyforanimals.org](mailto:dataprivacy@mercyforanimals.org). You should be aware that the removal of content may not ensure the complete or comprehensive erasure of that information from the internet or third-party archives.

##### Additional questions and effective date

This policy is effective as of May 25, 2018, and may be amended from time to time. Any amendments to our Privacy Policy will be posted as a notification on this page. If you have questions about our Privacy Policy, please contact us at [dataprivacy@mercyforanimals.org](mailto:dataprivacy@mercyforanimals.org).

If you would like to view or make changes to your personal information, please contact us at [dataprivacy@mercyforanimals.org](mailto:dataprivacy@mercyforanimals.org) and an MFA representative will be happy to assist you.
